You're all selfish. We are all selfish.
>> Agree or [music] disagree? Choosing not
to have children is fundamentally
selfish.
>> I think [music] people tend to conflate
selfishness and self-interest. I believe
when normal people like you and I when
we decide whether or not we want to have
kids, it's almost always from a
self-interested point of view. So if
somebody says, "Oh, I actually really
want kids. I just choose not to to save
the environment or oh, I don't even want
kids. I'm just doing it for the economy.
I'll be very skeptical. Those have
always sounded more like retrospective
[music] rationalizations for a personal
decision that was much more influenced
by selfish decisions. But because the
choice of being child-free or to have
children is such a personal topic,
accusations start getting thrown around.
You're selfish for not having children.